Inventory of the Robert Saunders Letters 1829-1867
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Robert Saunders Letters 1829-1867
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2007.109
0.25
65 items.
This collection consists of 66 letters written by Robert Saunders of Williamsburg, Virginia to his wife Lucy Burwell Saunders (60 letters) and his daughters Lucy Page Saunders (3 letters) and Roberta P. Saunders (2 letters) from 1829-1867. There is also a letter written on May 4, 1847 to Overton Bernard, the father of College of William and Mary student Jesse Talbot Bernard.
Saunders, Robert, 1805-1868 arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center from Margaret P. Manlove on 12/05/2007.
Custodial History
A portion of this collection was previously part of the University Archives Faculty-Alumni File Collection. It was rehoused here 1/21/10.
Biographical Note
Robert Saunders was born 25 January 1805 in Williamsburg, Virginia. He attended the College of William and Mary and the University of Virginia. Saunders served as professor of mathematics at William and Mary from 1833 to 1848 and was president of the college 1847-1848. He was a captain in the Confederate States Army, head of Eastern State Hospital, mayor of Willamsburg, vestryman of Bruton Parish and served in the Virginia State Senate. Saunders married Lucy Burwell Page in 1828 and had, among other children, Roberta Saunders and Robert Page Saunders. He died 11 September 1868. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Robert Saunders.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 66 letters written by Robert Saunders of Williamsburg, Virginia to his wife Lucy Burwell Saunders (60 letters) and his daughters Lucy Page Saunders (3 letters) and Roberta P. Saunders (2 letters) from 1829-1867. There is also a letter written on May 4, 1847 to Overton Bernard, the father of College of William and Mary student Jesse Talbot Bernard.
Arrangement of Materials
The correspondence is arranged chronologically.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence
Geographic Name:
Williamsburg (Va.)--History--19th century.
Topical Term:
College of William and Mary--Alumni and Alumnae.; College of William and Mary--Faculty and Staff; College of William and Mary--Presidents.; Confederate States of America. War Dept.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- id24290 (Folder 1)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy at Hanover c/o Beverley Blair, Richmond, 16 September 1829; id24289 (Folder 1)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy at Hanover c/o Beverley Blair, Richmond, 3 October 1829; id24291 (Folder 1)
- id24313 (Folder 2)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy c/o Richard Anderson Esq. Richmond, 28 September 1832; id24346 (Folder 2)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy at Fauquier Springs Hanover, 30 August 1844; id24347 (Folder 2)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy at Warrenton Springs, 11 August 1845; id24348 (Folder 2)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy at Williamsburg, 2 February 1847; id24349 (Folder 2)
- id24350 (Folder 3)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 14 March 1852; id24351 (Folder 3)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 28 March 1852; id24352 (Folder 3)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 8 April 1852; id24353 (Folder 3)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy at Williamsburg, 22 April 1852; id24354 (Folder 3)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 25 April 1852; id24355 (Folder 3)
- id24361 (Folder 4)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 28 April 1852; id24356 (Folder 4)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 6 May 1852; id24357 (Folder 4)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 31 May 1852; id24358 (Folder 4)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 8 June 1852; id24359 (Folder 4)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy at Williamsburg, 31 January 1854; id24360 (Folder 4)
- id24368 (Folder 5)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy, 3 January 1860; id24369 (Folder 5)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 19 February 1860; id24362 (Folder 5)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy, 3 September 1860; id24363 (Folder 5)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy, 14 September 1860; id24364 (Folder 5)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 6 January 1861; id24365 (Folder 5)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy, 11 February 1861; id24366 (Folder 5)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy, 27 February 1861; id24367 (Folder 5)
- id24370 (Folder 6)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy at Taylorville, Hanover County, 12 September 1862; id24371 (Folder 6)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 16 November 1862; id24372 (Folder 6)
- id24373 (Folder 7)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 6 February 1863; id24374 (Folder 7)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 9 February 1863; id24375 (Folder 7)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 15 February 1863; id24454 (Folder 7)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 19 February 1863; id24455 (Folder 7)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 27 February 1863; id24456 (Folder 7)
- id24457 (Folder 8)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, at Pittsylvania C.H., 4 March 1863; id24458 (Folder 8)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy at Pittsylvania CH, 8 March 1863; id24459 (Folder 8)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 12 March 1863; id24460 (Folder 8)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 22 March 1863; id24461 (Folder 8)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 26 March 1863; id24462 (Folder 8)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 29 March 1863; id24463 (Folder 8)
- id24464 (Folder 9)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 5 April 1863; id24466 (Folder 9)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 12 April 1863; id24467 (Folder 9)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 14 April 1863; id24543 (Folder 9)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 26 April 1863; id24544 (Folder 9)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 3 May 1863; id24545 (Folder 9)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 31 May 1863; id24546 (Folder 9)
- id24465 (Folder 10)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 7 June 1863; id24547 (Folder 10)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 12 June 1863; id24548 (Folder 10)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 25 June 1863; id24549 (Folder 10)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 28 June 1863; id24571 (Folder 10)
  - Robert Saunders at “the Rectory” to his wife Lucy, 12 July 1863; id24572 (Folder 10)
  - Robert Saunders at Danville to his wife Lucy, 30 July 1863; id24573 (Folder 10)
- id24574 (Folder 11)
  - Robert Saunders at Rectory to his wife Lucy, 3 August 1863; id24578 (Folder 11)
  - Robert Saunders at Liberty, Bedford to his wife Lucy, 7 August 1863; id24579 (Folder 11)
  - Robert Saunders at Henry Court House to his wife Lucy, 7 September 1863; id24581 (Folder 11)
  - Robert Saunders at Henry Court House to his wife Lucy, 11 September 1863; id24583 (Folder 11)
  - Robert Saunders at Pittsylvania Court House to his daughter Lucy Page, 4 November 1863; id24593 (Folder 11)
- id24575 (Folder 12)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy, 17 March 1864; id24601 (Folder 12)
- id24576 (Folder 13)
  - Robert Saunders at Richmond to his wife Lucy at Pittsylvania Court House, 7 March 1865; id24607 (Folder 13)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy, 27 July 1865; id24611 (Folder 13)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy at Pittsylvania Court House, 13 August 1865; id24623 (Folder 13)
  - Robert Saunders at Washington to his wife Lucy, 27 August 1865; id24628 (Folder 13)
- id24577 (Folder 14)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his daughter Lucy Page at Pittsylvania Court House, 19 August 1867; id24629 (Folder 14)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy, 4 September 1867; id24630 (Folder 14)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his daughter, Roberta Page, 11 September 1867; id24635 (Folder 14)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy at Richmond, 11 September 1867; id24636 (Folder 14)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy at Pittsylvania Court House, 16 September 1867; id24637 (Folder 14)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his daughter Roberta Page, 25 September 1867; id24638 (Folder 14)
  - Robert Saunders at Williamsburg to his wife Lucy, 30 September 1867; id24639 (Folder 14)